Register of the Atlantic Council of the United States Records, 1950-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1950-1985
  - Regional conferences, clippings, 1965-66 (Folder 5)
  - Reid, Escott (Folder 6)
  - Reid, Ogden (Folder 7)
  - Reinstein, Jacques J.
    - Advisory Trade Panel, 1979 (Folder 8-10)
    - Correspondence
      - 1976 (227, Folder 1)
      - 1977
        - January-July (Folder 2)
        - July-December (Folder 3)
      - 1978 (Folder 4)
      - 1979 (Folder 5-6)
      - Leddy, John M., 1977-78 (Folder 7)
      - Trade Panel, 1978 (Folder 8)
      - U.S. Information Agency, 1978 (Folder 9)
    - Tokyo Round, 1978-79 (Folder 10)
    - Trade Panel
      - Atlantic Institute joint study, 1977
        - June-August (Folder 11)
        - September-December (Folder 12)
        - Various months (228, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - 1976 (Folder 2)
        - 1976-77 (Folder 3)
        - 1979 (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda to
        - 1976
          - March-July (Folder 5)
          - July-August (Folder 6)
          - September (Folder 7-8)
          - October-December (229, Folder 1)
        - 1977
          - January-February (Folder 2)
          - March (Folder 3)
          - April-May (Folder 4)
          - June (Folder 5)
          - July-September (Folder 6)
          - October (230, Folder 1)
        - 1978 (Folder 2-5)
      - Study (Folder 6)
    - Trip, European, June 1974 (Folder 7)
  - Rejected material, 1971 (Folder 8)
  - Rent
    - 1962 (Folder 9)
    - 1963 (Folder 10)
    - 1968 (Folder 11)
    - 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Reorganization (231, Folder 1)
  - Report of "Three Wise Men" (Folder 2)
  - Reporting, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Representation, public relations, promotion (Folder 4)
  - Reprint permissions, 1970 (Folder 5)
  - Republican Party (Folder 6)
  - Republican Platform Committee, 1972 (Folder 7)
  - Republicans for Progress (Folder 8-9)
  - Requests
    - 1969 (Folder 10)
    - 1974 (Folder 11)
    - 1976 (Folder 12)
  - Research projects
    - General (Folder 13)
    - Student unrest (232, Folder 1)
  - Research surveys
    - 1970-71 (Folder 2-5)
    - General (Folder 6-7)
    - General (233, Folder 1)
  - Retirement: TIAA/CREF
    - 1965-66 (Folder 2)
    - 1968 (Folder 3)
    - 1969 (Folder 4)
  - Reuss, Henry S. (Folder 5)
  - Ripon Society
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 6)
    - 1970-72 (Folder 7)
  - Robert College of Istanbul, Turkey (Folder 8)
  - Robotyping Letter Service, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Rockefeller book, responses to, 1968 (Folder 10)
  - Rockefeller Foundation
    - 1980 (Folder 11)
    - Special Committee proposal, 1974 (Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller Report (IEAL), 1978 (Folder 13)
  - Rolfe, Sidney E.
    - Capital Markets in Atlantic Economic Relationships, 1967 (Folder 14)
    - Report on Atlantic Institute Paris Technology Meeting, November 11, 1967 (Folder 15)
  - Romney, George, Trip to Europe, 1965 (Folder 16)
  - Roper, Elmo
    - General (234, Folder 1)
    - Roper Poll (Folder 2-3)
    - Survey, September 1963 (Folder 4-5)
  - Rostow, Dean, paper on political unity, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Rostow, Eugene V.
    - 1974-76 (Folder 7)
    - "The Battle of the American Mind,", 1969 (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1974-75 (Folder 9)
    - "Europe, the United States and the Free World," (Folder 10)
  - Roundtable for Business Executives on the Atlantic Community, March 24-26, 1965 (Folder 11)
  - Royaumont Report, July 1966 (Folder 12)
  - Rush, Kenneth
    - Correspondence
      - 1977-78 (Folder 13)
      - 1978 (Folder 14)
      - 1979 (235, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising, 1978 (Folder 2)
  - Rush, Secretary and Minister Werner, notes, May 1972 (Folder 3)
  - Ryan, John (Folder 4)
  - Safeguards Project
    - General (Folder 5)
    - American Nuclear Society Conference, October 1977 (Folder 6)
    - Bibliography (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1976-79 (Folder 8)
    - Davidoff, Barry, "The Nuclear Fuel Cycle,", 1976 (Folder 9)
    - Donnelly, Warren, "Materials for Bibliography" (Folder 10)
    - Funding research (Folder 11)
    - Meetings
      - (no year indicated), February 24 (Folder 12)
      - 1976
        - November 10 (Folder 13)
        - December 7 (236, Folder 1)
      - 1977
        - January 27 (Folder 2)
        - March 17 (Folder 3)
        - April 1 (Folder 4)
        - August 9-10 (Folder 5)
        - December 8 (Folder 6)
      - 1978 February 9 (Folder 7)
    - Preliminary planning (Folder 8)
    - Second draft (Folder 9)
    - Student interns (Folder 10)
    - U.S. Department of Energy (Folder 11)
    - Winkler, Theodor (Folder 12)
    - Writing assignments (Folder 13)
  - Salzburg Seminars
    - 1965 December 6 (Folder 14)
    - American Studies
      - 1964-67 (Folder 15)
      - 1974 (Folder 16)
  - Sampson, Edith S., "International Justice Through a NATO Court,", n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Sattler, James F. (237, Folder 1-2)
  - Saudi Arabia (Folder 3-4)
  - Scaife Foundation (nuclear), 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Scammon, Richard M. (Folder 6)
  - Schaetzel, J. Robert, "Institutional Lesson of the European Community,", January 6, 1975 (Folder 7)
  - Schmidt, Adolph W. (Folder 8-9)
  - Scholarships, 1966 (Folder 10)
  - School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS), Johns Hopkins University
    - 1973-75 (238, Folder 1)
    - 1977-79 (Folder 2)
  - Schroeder, Oliver, Jr.
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Folder 3)
    - "International Justice Through a NATO Court,", n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Science and technology, 1966-68 (Folder 5)
  - Science and Technology Committee
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Knoppers, Dr. Antonie (Folder 7)
  - Scowcroft, General (Folder 8)
  - S.D. Grant 1069-787091, January 1977 (Folder 9)
  - Sea Link
    - 1975 (Folder 10)
    - 1978 (Folder 11)
    - 1980 (Folder 12)
  - Secondary Schools (Folder 13)
  - Securing the Seas
    - General (239, Folder 1)
    - Invitations and replies (Folder 2)
    - List of members (Folder 3)
    - Meetings
      - 1st, September 30, 1976 (Folder 4)
      - 2nd, November 18, 1976 (Folder 5)
      - 3rd, January 13, 1977 (Folder 6)
      - 4th, February 24, 1977 (Folder 7)
      - 5th, April 7, 1977 (Folder 8)
      - 6th, May 19, 1977 (Folder 9)
      - 7th, June 30, 1977 (Folder 10)
      - 7A, August 11, 1977 (240, Folder 1)
      - 8th, September 22, 1977 (Folder 2)
      - 9th, November 3, 1977 (Folder 3-4)
      - 10th, December 15, 1977 (Folder 5)
      - 11th, January 26, 1978 (Folder 6-7)
      - 12th, March 9, 1978 (Folder 8)
      - 13th, April 12, 1978 (Folder 9)
      - 14th, June 29, 1978 (Folder 10)
    - Policy papers sales, 1979 (241, Folder 1)
    - Press conference, November 15, 1978 (Folder 2)
    - Study group (Folder 3-8)
  - "Security and Detente Policy: Considerations for Japan, North America, and Europe,", July 1973 (Folder 9)
  - Security in the Eastern Mediterranean (Folder 10)
  - Security in the Eastern Mediterranean (242, Folder 1)
  - Security Working Group
    - 1975 (Folder 2)
    - 1976 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1976-77 (Folder 5-6)
    - 1977 (Folder 7)
    - 1977-78 (Folder 8)
    - General (Folder 9)
    - General (243, Folder 1-2)
    - Achilles, Theodore C. (Folder 3)
    - Clippings and notes (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1977-78 (Folder 5)
    - LeBourgeois, Julien, "What is the Soviet Navy Up To?", 1976 (Folder 6)
    - List of members (Folder 7)
    - Luttwak paper (Folder 8)
    - Meetings
      - 1976 May 21 (Folder 9)
      - 1977 April 21 (Folder 10)
      - 1978 November 28 (Folder 11)
      - 1979 January 24 (Folder 12)
    - Organization, 1975 (244, Folder 1)
    - Press coverage (Folder 2)
    - Replies to report letter (Folder 3)
    - Vogt paper, 1977 (Folder 4)
    - Wolf, Joseph W. (Folder 5)
  - Security Working Group and Political Committee I (Folder 6)
  - Seminars
    - 1965 December 5-6 (Folder 7)
    - "The Relationship Between Foreign Investment and Trade,", December 5-6, 1968 (Folder 8-10)
    - "The Relationship Between Foreign Investment and Trade,", December 5-6, 1968 (245, Folder 1-2)
    - "The Teaching of Values in Higher Education,", September 5, 1985 (373, Folder 5)
  - Seminars and conferences, 1964-68 (245, Folder 3)
  - Senate anti-trust and monopoly hearings, 1966 (Folder 4)
  - Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Folder 5)
  - Senate Concurrent Resolution No. 17 (Folder 6)
  - Senate Finance Committee (Folder 7)
  - Senate hearings on nuclear safeguards (Folder 8)
  - Senate Joint Resolution No. 170 (Folder 9)
  - Senate Resolution 78 (Folder 10)
  - Senate Subcommittee on National Security and International Operations (Folder 11)
  - Shape trip from Paris to Luxembourg, September 9, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Sharpless, William L. (Folder 14-3-14)
  - Sixth Biennial Atlantic Study Conference on Education, Lisbon, July 25-30, 1966 (246, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian luncheon group, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Society for Citizen Education in World Affairs (Folder 4)
  - South Africa and nuclear energy (Folder 5)
  - "Soviet Challenge Calls for More Than Military Response,", January 1978 (Folder 6)
  - Soviet naval threat, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Spain study, 1978 (Folder 8)
  - Speakers, 1966-68 (Folder 9)
  - Speaking engagements for various individuals (Folder 10)
  - Special Advisory Committee (Folder 11)
  - Special book project (Folder 12)
  - Special Committee
    - 1968-69 (Folder 13)
    - 1969 (Folder 14)
    - 1975 (Folder 15)
    - 1975 March (247, Folder 1-2)
    - Proposal draft (Folder 3)
    - United Nations Working Group (Folder 4)
    - Working groups (Folder 5)
  - Special Committee on Atlantic Organizations
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Achilles, Theodore C., memoranda, 1975
      - January 20 (Folder 7)
      - February 19 (Folder 8)
    - Meeting, January 17, 1975 (Folder 9)
  - Special Committee on Improving Relations with Congress and the Executive Branch (Folder 10)
  - Special Committee on Intergovernmental Organization and Reorganization
    - 1974 (Folder 11)
    - General (Folder 12)
    - General (248, Folder 1-2)
    - Achilles, Theodore C.
      - Memoranda
        - 1974 (Folder 3)
        - 1975 (Folder 4)
      - Preliminary paper on NATO deficiencies, November 1974 (Folder 5)
    - Burgess, W. Randoph
      - "Effectiveness of the OECD,", November 26, 1974 (Folder 6)
      - Memoranda, November 26, 1974 (Folder 7)
    - Cooper, Richard N. (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - 1974 (Folder 9)
      - 1975 (Folder 10)
    - Draft outline, work pattern (Folder 11)
    - German Marshall Fund (Folder 12)
    - Interim report (Folder 13)
    - Invitation letter, September 5, 1974 (Folder 14)
    - Meetings
      - 1974
        - October 1 (Folder 15)
        - October 28 (Folder 16)
        - December 2 (249, Folder 1)
      - 1975
        - January 17 (Folder 2)
        - May 30 (Folder 3)
    - Membership (Folder 4)
    - Merchant, Livingston T., "Shortcomings of the IBRD," l975, January 3 (Folder 5)
    - North Atlantic Assembly (Folder 6)
    - Owen, Henry, "International Organization,", January 17, 1975 (Folder 7)
    - Preliminary working papers (Folder 8)
    - Revised outline, February 2-6, 1975 (Folder 9)
    - Sonnenfeldt, paper to, December 13, 1974 (Folder 10)
    - Summary record, December 2, 1974 (Folder 11)
    - Trade papers (Folder 12)
    - Wallace, Richard, memoranda, October 30, 1974 (Folder 13)
    - Wyndham-White, Eric (Folder 14)
  - Special Committee on International Organization
    - Meeting, March 19, 1975 (Folder 15)
    - Memoranda, 1975
      - February 14 (Folder 16)
      - March 18 (Folder 17)
  - Special Governmental Commission
    - 1963-64 (Folder 18)
    - General (250, Folder 1-2)
  - Special Government Commission on Atlantic Unity (Hickerson Commission) (Folder 3-4)
  - Special mailings (Folder 5)
  - Special projects
    - Book re: Conference, 1969 (Folder 6)
    - McDonnell NATO dinner, April 1969 (Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 8)
  - Special studies (Folder 9)
  - Special Trade Panel, 1973 (Folder 10-11)
  - Speech material (Folder 12)
  - Sponsor, definition of, 1963 (Folder 13)
  - Sponsor correspondence
    - 1966-67 (Folder 14)
    - 1970 (Folder 15)
  - Sponsor lists, April 1963 (Folder 16)
  - Standing Conference of Atlantic Organizations
    - 1975 (251, Folder 1)
    - 1977-79 (Folder 2)
  - Stanford in Washington (Folder 3-4)
  - Stanford University
    - 1980-81 (Folder 5)
    - International Studies Program, 1967 (Folder 6)
  - Stanley, Timothy
    - General (Folder 7-11)
    - "A Conference on European Security? Problems, Pros- pects, and Pitfalls,", January 28, 1970 (252, Folder 1)
    - European Security Conference (Folder 2)
    - Statement before the House Ways and Means Committee, May 14, 1973 (Folder 3)
  - Stanley Foundation Conference, October 1977 (Folder 4)
  - State Department grant, 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Statement, 1968
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Response to (Folder 7)
  - Steering Committee of the Special Committee, Trilateral papers, Hauge speech (Folder 8)
  - Steinberg, David J., "A Critique on the Administration's Trade Bill and Trade Message,", January 1970 (Folder 9)
  - Stiftung Wissenschaft und Politik, 1974 (Folder 10)
  - Stikker, Dirk U.
    - Reception for, June 4, 1964 (Folder 11)
    - Statement at National Press Club of Washington, March 8, 1963 (Folder 12)
  - Stonier School of Banking (Folder 13)
  - Stoopack/Gross proposal (Folder 14)
  - Straus, Ralph I., "Future of U.S. Foreign Trade Policy," report, March 20, 1968 (253, Folder 1)
  - "Strengthening the International Monetary System,", June 1967 (Folder 2)
  - "Strengthening the North Atlantic Treaty Organization,", January 1979 (Folder 3)
  - The Studies Centre for the Atlantic Community, a preliminary prospectus, October 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Study Group, 1966-1980 (Folder 5)
  - Sub-Committee on an Atlantic Colloquium, meeting, September 11, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - Sub-Committee on Graduate Study Abroad, meeting, September 11, 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Successor Generation
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Student meetings (Folder 9)
    - Working Group
      - 1979-1980 (Folder 10)
      - General (Folder 11)
  - "Summits and Collective Leadership in the 1980s,", March 1980 (254, Folder 1)
  - Supplies, 1971 (Folder 2)
  - Survey on Investment Climate for American Business in Europe (Folder 3-4)
  - Survey poll, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Swarthmore Conference, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - Swezey, Burr S. (Folder 7)
  - Symposium on Relationship Between Trade and Investment, August 29, 1968 (Folder 8)
  - Taxes
    - 1963 (Folder 9)
    - 1968 (Folder 10)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, College Retirement Equities Fund (Folder 11)
  - Technology, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Technology and Foreign Affairs Study
    - 1976 (Folder 13-14)
    - 1976 (255, Folder 1-3)
    - Interviews (Folder 4)
  - Technology transfers, 1974 (Folder 5)
  - Telephone and telegraph expenses
    - 1962 (Folder 6)
    - 1963 (Folder 7)
  - Telephones, 1969 (256, Folder 1-2)
  - Terrell, Henry S., "The Fiscal Impact of Negroes on Central Cities,", February 1969 (Folder 3)
  - Thompson, J. Walter, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - A Three-Year Program of Assessment, Planning, and Development for the Atlantic Council of the United States, July 18, 1984 (Folder 5)
  - Trabuc, Claude, "Tariff Preferences for the Developing Countries,", November 1969 (Folder 6)
  - Trade
    - 1979-1981 (Folder 7)
    - General (Folder 8)
    - General (257, Folder 1-4)
    - AFL/CIO, 1973-74 (Folder 5)
    - Committee for a National Trade Policy, 1972-73 (Folder 6)
    - Council statement, April 1973 (Folder 7)
    - Negotiations, 1972-73 (Folder 8)
    - Statements (Folder 9)
  - Trade Committee
    - 1965-69 (Folder 10)
    - 1973 (258, Folder 1-6)
    - 1974-75 (Folder 7)
    - 1975-77 (Folder 8)
    - General (259, Folder 1)
    - Drafts and working papers (Folder 2)
    - Minutes, March 21, 1973 (Folder 3)
    - Reinstein, J. J. (Folder 3A)
    - Report, February 14, 1973 (Folder 4)
    - Special Trade Panel (Folder 4A)
    - Statement, February 14, 1973 (Folder 5)
  - Trade Conference, Paris, June 1977 (Folder 5A)
  - Trade legislation, 1974 (Folder 6)
  - Trade liberalization, 1975 (Folder 6A)
  - Trade panels, clippings, 1976-79 (Folder 6B)
  - Trade Reform Act, 1973
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Eberle, William D., testimony before the Senate (Folder 8)
    - House debate, December 10, 1973 (Folder 9)
    - House hearings and Senate (260, Folder 1)
  - Trade statement, February 14, 1973 (Folder 2)
  - Trade talks, 1973 (Folder 3)
  - Trade-agriculture (Folder 4)
  - Translations
    - 1964-69 (Folder 5)
    - 1968 (Folder 6)
  - Travel expenses
    - 1962 (Folder 7)
    - 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's reports
    - 1962 (Folder 9)
    - 1963 (Folder 10)
    - 1964 (Folder 11)
    - 1965 (Folder 12)
    - 1968 (261, Folder 1)
  - Trilateral Commission, 1972-77 (Folder 2)
  - Turkey (Folder 3)
  - Turkish Atlantic Association, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Turkish embargo, April 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Tuthill, John W.
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Folder 6)
    - Finances, 1969-1971 (Folder 7)
  - UNA-USA, 1965-66 (Folder 8)
  - Unemployment tax
    - 1963 (Folder 9)
    - 1968 (Folder 10)
  - United Nations
    - 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Atlantic Council, working group on (262, Folder 1)
    - Bond issue, 1962 (Folder 2)
    - General Assembly, Special Session, April-May 1974 (Folder 3)
    - Working Group
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, 1975-76 (Folder 5)
      - Drafts and reports (Folder 6)
  - United Publishing Company, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - United States
    - Congress, House of Representatives, H.R. 14870, Trade Act of, 1979 (Folder 8)
    - Department of Defense (Folder 9)
    - Department of State
      - 1968-69 (Folder 9A)
      - 1970 (Folder 10)
      - 1970-71 (Folder 11)
      - 1972 (Folder 12)
      - Grantree permanent record card (263, Folder 1)
      - Press releases, 1961-62 (Folder 2)
      - Reception list, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Newspapers (Folder 4)
    - President's Committee to Study the U.S. Military Assistance Program, Letter to the President and Committee's Third Interim Report, "Economic Assistance Programs and Administration,", July 13, 1959 (Folder 5)
    - Trade negotiations, 1972-73 (Folder 6)
    - Treasury (Folder 7)
  - "U.S. Agriculture in a World Context,", 1971 (Folder 8)
  - "U.S. Agriculture in a World Context: Policies and Approaches for the Next Decade" (Folder 9-12)
  - "U.S. Agriculture in a World Context: Policies and Approaches for the Next Decade" (264, Folder 1)
  - "The U.S. and the Developing Countries"
    - 1977 October (Folder 2)
    - Draft report, November 1976 (Folder 3)
  - U.S. Citizens Commission on NATO
    - 1961
      - April-June (Folder 4)
      - July-August (Folder 5)
      - September-October (Folder 6)
      - November (Folder 7)
      - December (265, Folder 1)
    - 1962 March (Folder 2)
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Agger, Donald G. (Folder 4)
    - letter to Parliaments of NATO nations, April 24, 1961 (Folder 5)
    - Atlantic Convention of NATO Nations, Paris, January 1962
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Agenda (Folder 7)
      - Hotel reservations (Folder 8)
      - Preparation for (Folder 9)
      - Rules (Folder 10)
    - Belgium (Folder 11)
    - Biographical data on Commission members (Folder 12)
    - Burden, William (Folder 13)
    - Canada (266, Folder 1)
    - Clayton, William L.
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Paper on European Common Market, August 14, 1961 (Folder 3)
      - Statement before the Senate Appropriations Com- mittee (budget hearing), June 4, 1961 (Folder 4)
    - Clayton-Herter letters to Congressmen re: budget, 1962 (Folder 5)
    - Clayton-Herter report on trip to Europe, May 1961 (Folder 6)
    - Congressional sponsors (Folder 7)
    - Congressmen, letters received from, re: time extension (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1962
      - January (Folder 9)
      - February (Folder 10)
      - April (Folder 11)
      - May-June (Folder 12)
    - Denmark (Folder 13)
    - Development of the NATO Parliamentarians Conference into an Atlantic Assembly, 1962 (Folder 14)
    - Engelhard, Charles (Folder 15)
    - Expenses, receipts (Folder 16)
    - Fact sheet, January 1962 (Folder 16A)
    - Feldman, George J.
      - General (Folder 17-18)
      - "The Operations and Activities of the Post-war European Organizations," (267, Folder 1)
      - Report, June 17, 1961 (Folder 2)
      - Report on trip to Scandinavia and Iceland, May 1961 (Folder 3)
      - Trip to Denmark and Iceland (Folder 4)
    - Fenner, Edward (Folder 5)
    - Finley, Martha C. (Folder 6)
    - Forgash, Morris (Folder 7)
    - France (Folder 9)
    - Germany (Folder 10)
    - Greece (Folder 11)
    - H.J. Resolution 463, June 30, 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Hartley, Livingston
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Comments on main conclusion of draft report of, March 14 (Folder 14)
      - "Development of NATO PC into an Atlantic Assem- bly,", April 16, 1963 (Folder 15)
      - "Possible Approaches to Greater Political Unity within NATO by Adaptation of European Methods,", September 29, 1961 (Folder 16)
    - Herter, Christian A.
      - General (268, Folder 1)
      - Trip to Canada, June 12-13, 1961 (Folder 2)
    - Herter-Clayton trip, 1961 (Folder 3)
    - Hutchins, Francis S.
      - General (Folder 4-5)
      - "Cultural Needs of the Atlantic Community,", n.d. (Folder 6)
    - Iceland (Folder 7)
    - Implications of population growth for the West, Decem- ber, 1, 1961 (Folder 8)
    - Italy (Folder 9)
    - Johnson, Eric (Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Folder 11)
    - Kefauver, Estes (Folder 12)
    - Knowland, William F. (Folder 13)
    - Labberton, Otto van H. (Folder 14)
    - Legal background (Folder 15)
    - Legislation pertaining to, 1962 (269, Folder 1)
    - Library of Congress (Folder 2)
    - Luxembourg (Folder 3)
    - Meany, George (Folder 4)
    - Meetings
      - 1961
        - April (Folder 5)
        - June 16-17 (Folder 6)
        - August 14-15 (Folder 7)
        - October 12-13 (Folder 8)
        - December 9-10 (Folder 9)
      - 1962
        - March 8 (Folder 10)
        - April 6 (Folder 11)
    - Members (Folder 12)
    - Memoranda to Commission members, April-May 1962 (Folder 13)
    - Moore, Hugh (Folder 14-15)
    - NATO Parliamentarians touring the U.S., July 9-21, 1961 (Folder 16)
    - Netherlands (Folder 17)
    - Norway (Folder 18)
    - Office space (Folder 19)
    - Passport corresondence (270, Folder 1)
    - Pittman, Ralph (Folder 2)
    - Portugal (Folder 3)
    - Press releases
      - 1961
        - April 7 (Folder 4)
        - April 26 (Folder 5)
        - April 28 (Folder 6)
        - June 16 (Folder 7)
        - August 13 (Folder 8)
        - August 15 (Folder 9)
        - October 12 (Folder 10)
        - December 11 (Folder 11)
      - Undated (Folder 12-13)
    - Proposed agenda for IPC and notes (Folder 14)
    - Regan, Ben (Folder 15)
    - Requests for information (Folder 16-17)
    - Roper, Elmo (271, Folder 1-2)
    - Rosenbloom, Morris V. (Folder 3)
    - Rostow, Eugene V. (Folder 4)
    - Rusk, Dean (Folder 5)
    - Sampson, Edith (Folder 6)
    - Schmidt, Adolf W. (Folder 7)
    - Schroeder, Oliver, Jr.
      - General (Folder 8)
      - "Some Reflections on Sovereignty,", n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Semi-annual report to the Vice President and Speaker of the House of Representatives (Folder 10)
    - Statement of an economic report in preparation for the U.S. Citizens Commission on NATO under the direc- tion of Charles W. Engelhard (Folder 11)
    - Streit, Clarence K. (Folder 12)
    - Study on Each of the NATO Countries, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - Supplemental bill (Folder 14)
    - Swezey, Burr (272, Folder 1)
    - Telegrams (Folder 2)
    - Thornton, A. Roland (Folder 3)
    - Travel orders (Folder 4)
    - Travel receipts (Folder 5)
    - Turkey (Folder 6)
    - United Kingdom Citizens Commission on NATO (Folder 7)